<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CyBlog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CyBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:30:52 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Connecting Information Security and the U.S. Healthcare: An Information Security Professional&#39;s Detailed Guide to the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996, Title II - Administrative Simplification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/hipaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 22:30:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/hipaa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Similar to my previous post regarding RFC 6598 and Network Address Translation (NAT), when I was still studying for my master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Information Security (InfoSec), I was tasked to present the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996 and how it relates to InfoSec. Being in this industry we are often tasked with safeguarding sensitive personal information, and this may include protected health information (PHI). HIPAA of 1996 establishes a standard for protecting sensitive health information of patients from unauthorized disclosures [&lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt;]. However, understanding HIPAA of 1996 and how to comply with it as an InfoSec professional can be daunting due to its scope and complexity. In this blog post, I will try to make HIPAA of 1996 digestible and highlight available tools and resources to assist professionals in their journey to compliance. I hope this blog post can become a single-page reference or guide in understanding HIPAA in the context of InfoSec.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overcoming IPv4 Private Address Overlaps in Large Business-to-Business Network Scenarios with Virtual Routing and Address Translations Using RFC 6598 Shared Address Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/nat-rfc6598/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/nat-rfc6598/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was our final Networking report paper during my master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Information Security (InfoSec) that we did not try to publish. The topic and initial router configurations were presented by my group mate, E.C. However, I had to make some changes to the provided router configurations and network architecture to remediate the issues we faced in the lab. I deployed the lab environment and revised router configuration using GNS3, then wrote our report paper, which you see now below. I decided to post this in my personal blog since there are limited resources out there relating to this topic and the hope that this will fill in certain knowledge gaps. As a matter fact, I had troubles researching and understanding certain concepts because of this limitation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ___________________________________________&#xA;    / I think it already has; my human looks at \&#xA;    \ the screen more than the real world.      /              &#xA;    -------------------------------------------&#xA;                \&#xA;                \&#xA;                \  |\__/,|   (`\&#xA;                _.|o o  |_   ) )&#xA;                -(((---(((--------&#xA;&#xA;                           ______________________&#xA;                          / Do you think AI will \&#xA;                          \ enslave humanity?    /&#xA; _._     _,-&amp;#39;&amp;#34;&amp;#34;`-._        ----------------------&#xA;(,-.`._,&amp;#39;(       |\`-/| /&#xA;    `-.-&amp;#39; \ )-`( , o o)&#xA;          `-    \`_`&amp;#34;&amp;#39;-&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Tyrone Kevin Ilisan, a PH Licensed Electronics Engineer and cyber blue teamer (Incident Responder) passionate about everything information security, cybersecurity, networks, space, and developing open-source tools that can hopefully help secure the cyberspace. I have a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Electronics Engineering (Telecommunication Engineering focused) and a Master&amp;rsquo;s in Information Security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
